<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Roman - sysadmin experience</title><link>https://invizus.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Roman - sysadmin experience</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 11:00:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://invizus.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thoughts on having my own homelab</title><link>https://invizus.github.io/posts/why-no-homelab/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 11:00:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://invizus.github.io/posts/why-no-homelab/</guid><description>A lot of folks in /r/homelab have their own homelab at their homes. Servers, storage, patch panels, and so on.
Luckily in my past jobs I had some hands on experience with enterprise servers like HP DL360, c7000 chassis, network equipment and firewalls and some more. I even got a chance to participate in designing infrastructure in a new datacentre. That covers the experience bit with hardware. Fiddling with hardware is great part of experience, but it does not require that much time as the software part of system and infrastructure administratrion.</description></item><item><title>Motivate</title><link>https://invizus.github.io/motivate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 23:25:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://invizus.github.io/motivate/</guid><description>Focus On Learning and Creating Rather Than Entertainment and Distraction
https://medium.com/the-mission/focus-on-learning-and-creating-rather-than-being-entertained-and-distracted-e6573de1bc84
Wake up at 5 am
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eGWrGFlYtAQ</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://invizus.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 22:49:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://invizus.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hi there. I am Linux system admin, DYI beginner and as much as I hate talking about food, I like to cook and try new things. I also read sometimes, I read normal books, a bit about science and sometimes blog posts.
Tech I administer Linux and I think Linux is great for scripting, automating things, doing infrastructure as code. So that is what I do.
Linux Ansible, Terraform AWS, GCP Then I like doing observability and security:</description></item><item><title>How to SSL</title><link>https://invizus.github.io/posts/ssl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:06:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://invizus.github.io/posts/ssl/</guid><description>Nowadays you do not need to know how to do SSL, because a lot of website providers do it for you. However if you want to create SSL website yourself, it is an easy task.
Just enabling SSL on your apache config will not work. Like, why? It is baffling! There is a reason to that which I will discuss in other posts, but for now lets proceed.
You would need three things for HTTPS to work.</description></item><item><title>SIEM. Why scoping environment is important.</title><link>https://invizus.github.io/posts/siem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 23:52:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://invizus.github.io/posts/siem/</guid><description>SIEM stands for Security Information and Event Management. Log management and notifications is a part of PCI DSS requirements and not optional in case of SAQ D.
Activity on your network should be logged and sent to SIEM for analysis. Such activity includes user activity on workstations and servers, also various system events on your network - servers, firewalls, switches. Logs from your network can be used in event of breach to rebuild a picture what was happening.</description></item></channel></rss>