<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Roman - sysadmin experience</title><link>https://invizus.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Roman - sysadmin experience</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 11:50:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://invizus.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My DevOps cloud lab in AWS with Terraform</title><link>https://invizus.github.io/posts/my-first-cloudlab/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 11:50:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://invizus.github.io/posts/my-first-cloudlab/</guid><description>Second edition.
I have writtem some DevOps&amp;rsquo;y scripts to setup and tear down cloud infrastructure for learning and experiments.
So lets have a look at what have I done so far.
Terraform is popular choice and easy tool for defining infrastructure in AWS/GCP/Azure, you can even use it for your self hosted LXD nodes or clusters.
It opensource community it is accepted practice to store your reusable (terraform) modules in separate git repositories.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on having my own homelab</title><link>https://invizus.github.io/posts/why-no-homelab/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 11:00:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://invizus.github.io/posts/why-no-homelab/</guid><description>Have you even been browsing /r/homelab on reddit? A lot of people there like to fiddle with hardware. And I mean some of them setup actual server rack in their own home! And they fill it up with patch panels, cables, network equipment and even servers.
But it takes a lot of space, produces good amount of noise and burns electricity.
I was lucky to work as a sysadmin and get my hands on all that stuff, and even design and set it up myself.</description></item><item><title>How to SSL</title><link>https://invizus.github.io/posts/ssl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:06:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://invizus.github.io/posts/ssl/</guid><description>Nowadays you do not need to know how to do SSL, because a lot of website providers do it for you. However if you want to create SSL website yourself, it is an easy task.
Just enabling SSL on your apache config will not work. Like, why? It is baffling! There is a reason to that which I will discuss in other posts, but for now lets proceed.
You would need three things for HTTPS to work.</description></item><item><title>SIEM. Why scoping environment is important.</title><link>https://invizus.github.io/posts/siem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 23:52:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://invizus.github.io/posts/siem/</guid><description>SIEM stands for Security Information and Event Management. Log management and notifications is a part of PCI DSS requirements and not optional in case of SAQ D.
Activity on your network should be logged and sent to SIEM for analysis. Such activity includes user activity on workstations and servers, also various system events on your network - servers, firewalls, switches. Logs from your network can be used in event of breach to rebuild a picture what was happening.</description></item></channel></rss>